Guan Wang

Wuhan, CN vonguan@gmail.com +8618049713638

Senior software engineer with rich experience in big data field, cloud dev/ arch experience and web dev/arch experience, In terms of project management, I has long-term agile scrum and DevOps practice in many projects. I hold several certifications, which can prove my capabilities in cloud, project management and DevOps field. I have good Chinese and English communication skills

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Personal Details

Date of Birth: 1986-03-28

Work Experience

Tecnical Manager

Accenture - 上海市 April 2017 to January 2023

- 1. Led a team to build a big data cluster based on Hortonworks on AWS, providing distributed data storage and computing capabilities to support batch and stream data processing. Our team is responsible for building and maintaining the platform, which covered most of the services shiped with hortonworks suite. Our team helps more than 5 big data projects onboard this platform.
- 2. Developed jobs to run on top of the platform, typically the jobs are composed with Talend as ETL tool, Spark as data processing component, Kafka Coneect as data ingestion tool, HDFS as raw data store and HDFS or mysql as insight data store.
- 3. Led a dev team to develop a web site built on hybird cloud solution, which use AWS to run frontend project and bind CDN service, and use GCP severless service to run backend and store data. in the whole project we use terraform to build or destroy infrastructure in AWS or GCP through the Azure Devops pipeline. both frontend and backend projects are released to online using CI/CD pipeline. In this project, our team achieved very good results, significantly reducing the development time while ensuring the quality of delivery, thanks to the implementation of DevOps and IaC strategies
- 4. Engeaged in several specific projects, collaborate with agile coach to take the agile practice, tasks include but not limited: kickoff meetings, collect requirements, brain stormings, planning meetings, making up epic/feature/product backlog/sprint backlog, daily meeting, retros meeting, evaluate tasks, review scopes/timeline/milestone/risks, reivew architecute design/code/test cases etc.
- 5. Led research on Azure DevOps, delving into the capabilities it offers, integrating this tool with our project's code management, building, and deployment. Depended on this tool throughout the software lifecycle, driving our team to use it effectively. Detailed strategies were formulated for code branching, tagging, code reviews, building and deployment standards, and test case specifications to enhance release efficiency and transparency.
- 6. Led a pioneer team to launch a first migration project when application migrate from on-premise data center to GCP in order to leverage GCP's various service capabilities. As technical manger in the

team, I am responsible for migration path and architecture design. Our team successfully migrated six applications to GCP according to different migration principles, such as lift-and-shift principle or cloud native principle or replacing principle or retiring principle, just based on the specific scenarios.

Data Engineer

Infosys - 上海市 October 2014 to March 2017

- 1. Engaged in Yum's log analytics project, which is Infosys' first big data delivery project, utilizing hadoop technology and business analytics combined in a typical project. I was responsible for the scripts for data cleansing and data processing, and ported the final processed metrics data table to Mysql via Sqoop. In this project we tried to utilize Jenkins to build automated job streaming and get email alerts when jobs fail. By monitoring the cluster hosts, we can keep an eye on the operation of the timed Hadoop jobs, which improves the maintainability and observability of the project, and is highly praised by Esaote.
- 2. Engaged in the company's self-developed intelligent building project, I am responsible for the design and construction of the data display function and rule engine of the project. The data display is to use HighChart to display the status or history information of some indicators of the smart building, and Angular is used to build SPA on the front-end page, and asynchronous loading is used in the place of multilevel menus, thus solving a page performance problem. Rule engine is built in Java to deal with the rules of a specialized subproject to Spark program to call. The rules engine is flexible enough to allow spark to accept complex rules and act accordingly. This good code practice was well received by the leadership.
- 3. As a data engineering consultant, I was assigned to Huawei to participate in its internal self-research project, which needed to migrate some applications which use Oracle as data store to Hadoop platform. In the process of migration, the Oracle SQL also needed to be modified for Hive , tasks such as SQL modifications , UDFs developements , job scheduling and monitoring need to be taken into consideration.

Web Developer

NewTouch - 上海市 July 2010 to September 2014

I was assigned to Communication bank to develop as web backend developer from 2012/10 - 2014/9

- 1. Developed web site for employees to communicate and help each other. I implemented some modules, such as vote module, SOS module
- 2. Developed crawler to crawl some pages based on the pre-configured website and topics at pre-configured schedule time, stored information into MangoDB.

I was assigned to China telecom to develop a third party payment software , aka BestPay which still is a popular payment channel in China

From 2010/7 - 2012/9

- 1. developed some exchange interfaces with some banks
- 2. developed and maintained a monitoring gateway system, which is for external system to audit or invoke.

Education

Bachelor's in Engineering

Lanzhou University of Technology - Lanzhou, CN September 2006 to July 2010

Skills

- Java (10+ years)
- Python (10+ years)
- DevOps (6 years)
- Kubernetes (3 years)
- Agile (6 years)
- Spring Boot (6 years)
- JavaScript (6 years)
- Spark (6 years)
- Hadoop (6 years)
- Scala (3 years)

Languages

- English Fluent
- Chinese Expert

Certifications and Licenses

AWS Certified Big Data Speciality

GCP Certified Professional Data Engineer

PMP

Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals

SAFe Certified DevOps Practitioner